[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions favours the existence of a substance in the solid state? ",
        "ansA": "High temperature ",
        "ansB": "Low temperature ",
        "ansC": "High thermal energy",
        "ansD": "Weak cohesive forces",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following conditions favours the existence of a substance in the solid state? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "A substance exists as solid only when ",
        "ansA": "intermolecular forces balance thermal energy",
        "ansB": "intermolecular forces are stronger than thermal energy",
        "ansC": "thermal energy dominates over intermolecular forces ",
        "ansD": "there are oppositely charged ions present. ",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "A substance exists as solid only when ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one has highest melting point? ",
        "ansA": "Ionic crystal",
        "ansB": "Molecular crystal",
        "ansC": "Covalent crystal ",
        "ansD": "Metallic crystal",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which one has highest melting point? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "In graphite, electrons are: ",
        "ansA": "localised on each carbon atom",
        "ansB": "spread out between the sheets",
        "ansC": "localised on every third carbon atom",
        "ansD": "present in antibonding orbital",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "In graphite, electrons are: ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wax is an example of ",
        "ansA": "Ionic crystal ",
        "ansB": "Covalent crystal",
        "ansC": "Molecular crystal ",
        "ansD": "Metallic crystal ",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Wax is an example of ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pseudo solid is : ",
        "ansA": "glass ",
        "ansB": "NaCl ",
        "ansC": "KCl",
        "ansD": "KCl and NaCI both",
        "ans": "a",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "A pseudo solid is : ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are solids rigid?",
        "ansA": "Because of large intermolecular forces ",
        "ansB": "Because of vibration motion",
        "ansC": "Because of large intermolecular space",
        "ansD": "All of the above ",
        "ans": "a",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Why are solids rigid?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a crystalline solid? ",
        "ansA": "Definite and characteristic heat of fusion ",
        "ansB": "Isotropic nature ",
        "ansC": "A regular periodically repeated pattern of arrangemet of constituent particles in the entire crystal",
        "ansD": "A true solid ",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a crystalline solid? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a network solid?",
        "ansA": "SO2 (Solid)",
        "ansB": 12,
        "ansC": "Diamond ",
        "ansD": "H2O (Ice) ",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following is a network solid?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "The constituent particles of a solid have",
        "ansA": "translatory motion only ",
        "ansB": "rotatory motion only ",
        "ansC": "vibratory motion only",
        "ansD": "all the above types of motion.",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "The constituent particles of a solid have",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following will have a low heat of fusion?",
        "ansA": "a covalent solid",
        "ansB": "an ionic solid ",
        "ansC": "a metallic solid ",
        "ansD": "a molecular solid ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which one of the following will have a low heat of fusion?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which among the following will show anisotropy?",
        "ansA": "Glass ",
        "ansB": "Barium chloride ",
        "ansC": "Wood ",
        "ansD": "Paper ",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which among the following will show anisotropy?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an amorphous solid?",
        "ansA": "Graphite (C) ",
        "ansB": "Quartz glass (SiO2)",
        "ansC": "Chrome alum ",
        "ansD": "Silicon carbide (SiC)",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following is an amorphous solid?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a crystalline solid?",
        "ansA": "KCI ",
        "ansB": "CsCl ",
        "ansC": "Glass ",
        "ansD": "Rhombic S ",
        "ans": "cv",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following is not a crystalline solid?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a covalent crystalline solid is",
        "ansA": "Si ",
        "ansB": "NaF ",
        "ansC": "Ar ",
        "ansD": "Al ",
        "ans": "a",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "An example of a covalent crystalline solid is",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amorphous substances show (A) Short and long range order (B) Short range order (C) Long range order (D) have no sharp m.p.",
        "ansA": "A and C are correct ",
        "ansB": "B and C are correct ",
        "ansC": "C and D are correct ",
        "ansD": "B and D are correct. ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Amorphous substances show (A) Short and long range order (B) Short range order (C) Long range order (D) have no sharp m.p.",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ststement is not true about amorphous solids? ",
        "ansA": "On heating they may become crystalline at ",
        "ansB": "They may become crystalline on keeping for ",
        "ansC": "Amorphous solids can be moulded by heating",
        "ansD": "They are anisotropic in nature ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following ststement is not true about amorphous solids? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Solid CO2 is an example of ",
        "ansA": "Ionic crystal ",
        "ansB": "Covalent crystal ",
        "ansC": "Metallic crystal ",
        "ansD": "Molecular crystal ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Solid CO2 is an example of ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which among the following will not show anisotropy?",
        "ansA": "BaCl2 ",
        "ansB": "NaCI ",
        "ansC": "Glass ",
        "ansD": "KN03 ",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which among the following will not show anisotropy?",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iodine crystals are: ",
        "ansA": "Metallic ",
        "ansB": "Ionic ",
        "ansC": "Molecular ",
        "ansD": "Covalent ",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Iodine crystals are: ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a substance possessing gaint covalent structure is: ",
        "ansA": "Iodine crystal",
        "ansB": "Silica ",
        "ansC": "Solid carbon dioxide",
        "ansD": "White phosphorus ",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "An example of a substance possessing gaint covalent structure is: ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of solid crystals will conduct heat and electricity ? ",
        "ansA": "Ionic ",
        "ansB": "Covalent ",
        "ansC": "Molecular ",
        "ansD": "Metallic ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which type of solid crystals will conduct heat and electricity ? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most crystals show good cleavage because their atoms, ions or molecules are",
        "ansA": "weakly bonded together ",
        "ansB": "strongly bonded together ",
        "ansC": "spherically symmetrical ",
        "ansD": "arranged in planes. ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Most crystals show good cleavage because their atoms, ions or molecules are",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "TeO2 is an example of ",
        "ansA": "Monoclinic system",
        "ansB": "Tetragonal system",
        "ansC": "Rhombic system ",
        "ansD": "Triclinic system ",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "TeO2 is an example of ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a molecular crystal? ",
        "ansA": "SiC ",
        "ansB": "NaCl ",
        "ansC": "Graphite ",
        "ansD": "Ice ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following is a molecular crystal? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not the characteristic of ionic solids? ",
        "ansA": "Very low value of electrical conductivity in the molten state ",
        "ansB": "Brittle nature ",
        "ansC": "Very strong forces of interactions ",
        "ansD": "Anisotropic nature ",
        "ans": "a",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Which of the following is not the characteristic of ionic solids? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which crystal will be soft and have low melting point? ",
        "ansA": "Covalent ",
        "ansB": "Ionic ",
        "ansC": "Metallic ",
        "ansD": "Molecular ",
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Among the following which crystal will be soft and have low melting point? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Graphite is a good conductor of electricity due to the presence of",
        "ansA": "lone pair of electrons",
        "ansB": "free valence electrons ",
        "ansC": "cations ",
        "ansD": "anions ",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Graphite is a good conductor of electricity due to the presence of",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcite belongs to",
        "ansA": "Tetragonal system",
        "ansB": "Trigonal system ",
        "ansC": "Digonal system",
        "ansD": "Hexagonal system",
        "ans": "b",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "Calcite belongs to",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of atoms per unit cell is 2, the arrangement is",
        "ansA": "octahedral ",
        "ansB": "fcc ",
        "ansC": "bee ",
        "ansD": "none of these ",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "The number of atoms per unit cell is 2, the arrangement is",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most unsymmetrical crystal system is",
        "ansA": "Cubic ",
        "ansB": "Hexagonal ",
        "ansC": "Triclinic ",
        "ansD": "Orthorhombic",
        "ans": "c",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "The most unsymmetrical crystal system is",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    },
    {
        "question": "The edge atom of a cube provides how many atoms to the unit cell ? ",
        "ansA": "1 /2",
        "ansB": "1 /4",
        "ansC": "1 /8",
        "ansD": 1,
        "ans": "d",
        "type": "text",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "explanation": "-",
        "explanationType": "text",
        "name": "The edge atom of a cube provides how many atoms to the unit cell ? ",
        "topic": "-KFA6e7SezMVRe9y24yb"
    }
]